const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="commerce",o=200,a=120,t=[{id:776,question:"The most effective type of advertising for branded products is",option:{a:"direct advertising",b:"indirect advertising",c:"informative advertising",d:"competitive advertising."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:585,question:"The first step for a businessman who wishes to engage in international trade is to",option:{a:"ask the exporter to move the goods to the shipping company for delivery",b:"engage the services of clearing agent to clear the goods on his behalf",c:"establish contact with the foreign trading partner",d:"fill an application for import form with a bank"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:535,question:"A counter-offer in a contract is regarded as",option:{a:"an acceptance",b:"an invitation to treat",c:"a rejection",d:"a consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:149,question:"Consumers require protection against exploitation to ensure ",option:{a:"adequate consumer awareness",b:"availability of product variety",c:"the sale of quality products",d:"increased aggregate demand."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:683,question:"Discharging certain duties by an organization to the public to gain high patronage is a concern of financial responsibility",option:{a:"economic responsibility.",b:"legal responsibility.",c:"financial responsibility.",d:"social responsibility."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:417,question:"A feature common to public and private limited liability companies is that ",option:{a:"both can sue and  be sued ",b:"the minimum number of their shareholders is five",c:"the transfer of their shares  is not restricted ",d:"their annual accounts are published for public use"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:266,question:"The principle of insurance which entitles an insurance company to take any advantage due to the insured after full indemnity is ",option:{a:"contribution  ",b:"subrogation ",c:"proximate cause ",d:"utmost good faith "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:189,question:"The function  of money that facilitates the comparison of the quality of goods as a basis of exchange is the   ",option:{a:"unit of account",b:"measure of value ",c:"store of value",d:"medium of exchange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:421,question:"If the rate of turnover of a company in 1999 was 4 times while the average stock was N49, 600, determine the turnover.",option:{a:"N199, 400",b:"N198, 400",c:"N100, 200",d:"N99, 200"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:256,question:"The most commonly used commercial documents are ",option:{a:"order notes, debit notes, invoices and quotations ",b:"letters of enquiry, consignment notes, receipts and invoices ",c:"credit notes, statement of accounts, dispatch order and bills ",d:"balance sheet, receipts, invoices and manifests."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:258,question:"If a buyer is given 12.5% discount on N50000 worth of goods, how much will he pay?",option:{a:"N56 250",b:"N43 750",c:"N43 250",d:"N6250"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:134,question:"‘Safeguarding the health of the nation' is the slogan used by ",option:{a:"NDLEA ",b:"NHIS ",c:"NAFDAC ",d:"EPI."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:725,question:"The practice whereby soft drink manufacturers give away caps, bags and other items when consumers buy their product is a 		form of",option:{a:"marketing strategy",b:"publicity",c:"advertising",d:"sales promotion."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:64,question:"A step-by-step method of carrying out functions in  an office is known as",option:{a:"procedure",b:"organizing",c:" policy ",d:"programme."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:457,question:"In order to increase the capital owned, a sole trader may ",option:{a:"seek for bank loan ",b:"issue debentures ",c:"acquire extra shop fittings on credit ",d:"draw less of his profit for personal use"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:106,question:"An important social reason for development tourism in Nigeria is the  ",option:{a:"promotion of culture interaction   ",b:" provision of job opportunities",c:"improvement of her balance of payments",d:"encouragement of international relations."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:802,question:"An author’s exclusive right to his published an unpublished works is known as",option:{a:"authors right",b:"constitutional right",c:"patent right",d:"copyright"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:327,question:"The tree components of staffing are ",option:{a:"recruitment, interview and appointment ",b:"recruitment, test and placement ",c:"recruitment, selection and appointment ",d:"recruitment, selection and placement "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:738,question:"The legal aspect of business is designed to",option:{a:"protect business organizations and consumers",b:"safeguard consumers from undue business practices",c:"protect infant industries from collapse",d:"encourage free exchanges among businesses."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:813,question:"The Stock Exchange is a market where",option:{a:"long-term securities are sold",b:"all types of securities are sold",c:"short-term securities are sold",d:"medium-term securities are sold."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:470,question:"The most suitable organizational structure for small or medium-sized enterprises is ",option:{a:"line structure ",b:"staff structure ",c:"committee structure ",d:"functional structure "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:822,question:"A contract for the sale of goods involves the",option:{a:"producer, seller and the buyer of goods",b:"offering of goods to customers",c:"transfer of the title to goods for money",d:"exchange of goods."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:162,question:"The sustainable growth of commerce is largely due to ",option:{a:"marketing   ",b:"advertising",c:"exchange ",d:"branding."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:730,question:"After registration, a certificate of trading is usually issued to a",option:{a:"partnership",b:"public company",c:"private company",d:"sole proprietorship."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:852,question:"The payment made periodically in respect of an insurance policy entered into is known as",option:{a:"bond",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"surrender value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:292,question:"A customer with XYZ Plc sent money through his account to his sister’s  account in another branch. This is an example of ",option:{a:"e-business",b:"e –commerce ",c:"e-finance ",d:"D e-banking "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:658,question:"The type of wholesaler that combines selling, delivery and collection in one operation is",option:{a:"specialist   wholesaler",b:"rack jobber",c:"drop shipment",d:"truck. wholesaler"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:784,question:"Departmentalization is an aspect of",option:{a:"planning",b:"organizing",c:"directing",d:"controlling."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:432,question:"A person who in consideration for an extra commission, takes responsibility for goods sold on credit and in case of default is a ",option:{a:"commission agent",b:"del credere agent ",c:"broker ",d:"factor "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:218,question:"A warehouse which is used to store goods whose customs duty is not yet paid is a ",option:{a:"wholesale warehouse",b:"bonded warehouse",c:"public warehouse",d:"branded warehouse"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:289,question:"Unresolved disputes between the employer and employees are usually referred to the ",option:{a:"code of conduct bureau",b:"personnel unit ",c:"disciplinary committee",d:"industrial arbitration tribunal "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:509,question:"Which of the following refers to a price reduction based on the size of order?",option:{a:"Cash discount",b:"Trade discount",c:"Seasonal discount",d:"Cash on delivery"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:864,question:"The business organization established mainly for the purpose of carrying out specific assignments for a specific duration is a",option:{a:"joint venture",b:"cooperative society",c:"partnership",d:"company."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:533,question:"Which of the following is not a means of consumer protection?",option:{a:"Price control",b:"Sale of Goods Act",c:"Trade Description Act",d:"Tax laws"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:668,question:"A formal letter to a dealer to enquire details about certain items for sale is referred to as",option:{a:"an inquiry",b:"an invoice",c:"an order",d:"a quotation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:586,question:"A law made by a country to prohibit importation of certain goods into the country is called _____ laws.",option:{a:"export",b:"import",c:"protectionist",d:"tariff"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:448,question:"The document which must be endorsed by the ambassador of a country of destination before shipment of goods is a ",option:{a:"consular invoice ",b:"certificate of origin ",c:"bill of lading ",d:"closed indent "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:682,question:"Labour as an input in production can be motivated by",option:{a:"training",b:"profit.",c:"remuneration.",d:"promotion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:811,question:"The bulls and bears in the Stock Exchange market help to minimize",option:{a:"the number of shares and bonds sold",b:"price increases of securities",c:"fluctuations in the prices of securities",d:"the elasticity of the prices of securities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:477,question:"An agent employed to sell goods delivered to him by the principal is referred to as a ",option:{a:"Special agent ",b:"del credere agent ",c:"factor ",d:"universal agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:753,question:"The difference between total current assets and total current liabilities of a business is known as",option:{a:"quick ratio",b:"liquidity ratio",c:"working capital",d:"circulating capital."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:754,question:"One of the reasons why wholesaling must continue is that",option:{a:"the tax paid by wholesalers on their profit enhances national revenue",b:"by creating artificial scarcity, the wholesaler is enhancing competition in the economy",c:"the wholesaler provides technical advice to the retailer",d:"the gap between manufacturers and retailers is reduced by wholesalers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:547,question:"Instrument used in place of legal tender but not freely acceptable are called ___ money.",option:{a:"bank",b:"commodity",c:"gold - backed",d:"representative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:226,question:"The resources which are necessary for business development include ",option:{a:"manufacturing, materials, mentors and money ",b:"merchant, materials, mentors and money",c:"man, money, materials and machines",d:"machines, manufacturing, money and materials"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:229,question:"Ships used for international transport are ",option:{a:"trawlers ",b:"yachts",c:"ocean liners ",d:"launchers "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:594,question:"In the marketing mix, place refers to",option:{a:"channel of distribution",b:"location of the factory",c:"the market place",d:"where the product is located"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:700,question:"The measure of independence available to the individual business units that come together is the main difference between",option:{a:"vertical and horizontal, integration",b:"mergers and acquisitions",c:"consortium and amalgamation",d:"trust and cartel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:460,question:"The amount of authorized capital that shareholders have subscribed to is ",option:{a:"issued share capital ",b:"authorized share capital ",c:"owner’s equity ",d:"working capital "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:475,question:"The breaking down of a market into separate and identifiable elements is known as ",option:{a:"differentiation ",b:"segmentation ",c:"skimming ",d:"penetration "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:46,question:"International fade takes place as a result of",option:{a:"uniformity in costs of production",b:"inequitable distribution of natural resources",c:"parity in the level of industrialization",d:"similarities in climatic conditions."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:170,question:"An economic activity which deals with natural resources is a form of  ",option:{a:"extraction",b:"refining   ",c:"construction ",d:"manufacturing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:384,question:"The body charged with the responsibility of regulating foods and drugs in Nigeria is the ",option:{a:"SON",b:"NDLEA",c:"NAFDAC",d:"CAC"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:795,question:"The agency that currently oversees the privatization and commercialization processes in Nigeria is the",option:{a:"Securities and Exchange Commission",b:"Technical Committee on Privatization and Commercialization",c:"Nigerian Stock Exchange",d:"Bureau of Public Enterprises."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:442,question:"The assembling of products into usable forms is known as ",option:{a:"creation ",b:"manufacturing ",c:"construction ",d:"formation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:506,question:"The production of goods in anticipation of demand is 	possible because of the existence of",option:{a:"Packaging",b:"advertising",c:"warehousing",d:"branding"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:282,question:"The daily official publications of the Nigerian Stock Exchange give detailed information on the ",option:{a:"changes in the official rules set by the market ",b:"method of transactions agreed upon by members ",c:"participation of members in a day ",d:"changes in the price of securities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:270,question:"Warehousing is important to manufacturers because it helps to ",option:{a:"improve the quality of goods ",b:"produce goods in advance",c:"meet the demand of customers ",d:"determine input requirements"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:575,question:"The following documents are used between buyers and sellers, EXCEPT",option:{a:"catalogue",b:"dispatch rate",c:"invoice",d:"license"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:85,question:"Which of the following confirms the accuracy of the duty charged on imported goods?",option:{a:" An indent ",b:"Consular invoice",c:" Consignment note  ",d:"Shipping note."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:752,question:"I.   Personal Savings, II.   Retained Earnings, III. Accrued Taxes. Which of the items above constitute internal sources of financing for companies?",option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and III",c:"II and III",d:"I, II and III."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:168,question:"The creation of utilities to satisfy human wants is referred to as   ",option:{a:"production  ",b:"consumption",c:"industrialization    ",d:"occupation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:617,question:"A business is in existence primarily to",option:{a:"make profit",b:"provide goods and services",c:"provide employment",d:"compete with others in business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:379,question:"Activities undertaken to create awareness for goods by conducting contests is ",option:{a:"marketing concept ",b:"consumerism ",c:"sales promotion ",d:"marketing mix"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:62,question:"The difference between personal selling and sales promotion is that while sales promotion includes free gifts and samples, personal selling involves",option:{a:"distributing instructional posters",b:"face-to-face communication with customers",c:"premium programming for customers",d:"publishing promotional booklets."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:801,question:"The commercialization of public enterprises aimed at",option:{a:"increasing efficiency and making the enterprises self-sufficient",b:"advertising a promoting the goods and services of the enterprises",c:"increased assistance and patronage of the enterprises by the public",d:"selling the goods and services of the enterprises."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:262,question:"The central bank differs from commercial banks  because it ",option:{a:"renders service to customers",b:"carriers but foreign exchange transactions ",c:"issues currencies ",d:"discounts bills"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:885,question:"Money can simply be referred to as a",option:{a:"medium of exchange",b:"means for the settlement of debts",c:"durable asset for doing business",d:"stands of value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:374,question:"Second-tier securities Market differs from the first-tier securities Market in that the former is ",option:{a:"Highly restricted ",b:"regulated by the SEC",c:"regulated by the NIPC",d:"Less restricted "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:290,question:"The process of eliminating a virus from a computer program is ",option:{a:"programming ",b:"debugging ",c:"formatting ",d:"looping"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:657,question:"A basic concept of advertising that reveals the essential message an advertiser wishes to communicate is referred to as the",option:{a:"medium",b:"theme",c:"target",d:"reach"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:78,question:"An engineer in government employ is to be rendering   ",option:{a:"primary service   ",b:"tertiary service ",c:"indirect service   ",d:"direct service. "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:570,question:"Double coincidence of wants is a disadvantage of",option:{a:"business",b:"buying and selling",c:"credit sales",d:"trade by barter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:615,question:"Which of the following is sent as a reply to an inquiry?",option:{a:"Tender",b:"Estimate",c:"Statement",d:"Quotation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:90,question:"The bank that discounts bills of exchange is the ",option:{a:"central bank  ",b:" mortgage bank",c:"development bank  ",d:"commercial bank."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:83,question:"A major function of a chamber of commerce is",option:{a:" increasing productivity",b:"promoting both home and foreign trade",c:"promoting trade in a particular line",d:" maximizing profit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:825,question:"Recognized members of the Stock Exchange who buy and sell securities on their own behalf are known as",option:{a:"bolls",b:"jobbers",c:"brokers",d:"stags."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:324,question:"A characteristic of money which ensures that its value is not lost is ",option:{a:"homogeneity ",b:"easy portability ",c:"divisibility ",d:"relative scarcity "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:827,question:"Which of the following is a function of employers’ association?",option:{a:"Undertaking research on behalf of employees",b:"Promotion of thrift in workers",c:"Promotion of workers’ welfare",d:"Dissemination of information through sponsored journals."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:751,question:"The financial instrument for borrowing in which the collateral is usually more than the amount borrowed is",option:{a:"trust certificate",b:"detachable warrant",c:"mortgage bond",d:"convertible securities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:531,question:"A contract of sale where ownership passes to the buyer on the payment of the first instalment is known as",option:{a:"hire purchase",b:"lease",c:"cash on delivery",d:"credit sale"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:780,question:"Who is the offeree in this contract?",option:{a:"Musa",b:"Audu",c:"Adamu",d:"Jacob."},section:"Musa rented a room to Adamu for N= 1, 500 and N= 1,000 part-payment was made. Adamu brought Audu and Jacob his friends to stay in the room. The two friends later paid the balance of N= 500 to Musa.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:817,question:"Given:  I.Retail; II.Export; III.Transport; IV.Import; V.Insurance; VI.Banking and finance; VII. Wholesale; VIII. Communication. Which of the above are aids to trade?",option:{a:"I, II,  III and VIII",b:"III, V, VI and VIII",c:"I, II, III and VI",d:"II, V, VI and VII"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:251,question:"Primary production is associated with ",option:{a:"banking ",b:"manufacturing ",c:"agriculture ",d:"construction "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:494,question:"The total value of fixed and current assets is?",option:{a:"working capital",b:"capital employed",c:"Fixed capital",d:"capital owned"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:863,question:"In the event of the liquidation of a company the first to be settled are",option:{a:"debenture holders",b:"members  of the  board",c:"preference shareholders",d:"ordinary shareholders."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:673,question:"Which of the following is a modern trend in retailing?",option:{a:"Kiosk",b:"Mobile shop",c:"Vending machine.",d:"Tied shop"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:755,question:"A merchant wholesaler is referred to as",option:{a:"del-credere agent",b:"a broker",c:"rack jobber",d:"a factor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:465,question:"Money is generally acceptable for transactions due to",option:{a:"the legal backing ",b:"the rule of law ",c:"it’s acceptability in the global market ",d:"the Central Bank Governor’s signature "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:115,question:"The main requirement for admission to the second-tier securities market is the ",option:{a:"provision of a three-year trading record   ",b:"disclosure of all trading activities   ",c:" creation of a good atmosphere for growth and development   ",d:"guaranteeing of dividends to shareholders."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:798,question:"A core investor in the current phase of privatization in Nigeria is one who",option:{a:"can afford to buy most the shares of the enterprises",b:"will be at the core of the enterprises",c:"can mobilize foreign currency equivalent to the value of the enterprises",d:"has the technical know-how of the enterprises"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:662,question:"The component of balance of payments which shows how the balance of both current and capital accounts are settled is 			known as",option:{a:"current account",b:"monetary movement account",c:"capital account.",d:"social welfare account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:58,question:"The primary objective of consumer protection laws is to ensure that consumers derive maximum satisfaction from goods and services",option:{a:"consumers buy goods and services at cheap rates   ",b:"manufacturers of goods and service providers overcome ",c:"Internal competition",d:"manufacturers of goods and service providers get optimum profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:363,question:"An ancillary to trade that easily links suppliers with consumers is ",option:{a:"tourism  ",b:"banking ",c:"communication ",d:"transportation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:299,question:"The reward of rent, wages, interest and profits accrue from",option:{a:"capitals, labour, land, and entrepreneur respectively",b:"land entrepreneur, labour and capital respectively",c:"land, labour, capital, and entrepreneur respectively",d:"labour, entrepreneur, land and capital respectively."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:679,question:"One of the functions of the Nigerian Ports Authority is that it",option:{a:"gives preferential treatment to Nigerian investors",b:"provides credit facilities to importers.",c:"encourages the growth of infant industries.",d:"provides warehousing facilities at the docks."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:623,question:"Which of the following is the quickest and accurate means of communication?",option:{a:"Telegram",b:"Express mail",c:"Courier services",d:"Telex"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:800,question:"Awarding scholarships and sponsoring sports by a business organization are examples of",option:{a:"advertising strategy",b:"economic responsibility",c:"marketing strategy",d:"social responsibility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:644,question:"The amount paid by the assured to the insurer is called",option:{a:"interest",b:"premium",c:"dividend",d:"indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:57,question:"The most dangerous pollution is",option:{a:"water ",b:"noise pollution",c:"soil pollution   ",d:"air pollution."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:383,question:"One of the obligations of an employer to an employee is to ",option:{a:"Indemnify  him against liabilities incurred on duty ",b:"award scholarship to his children ",c:"terminate his appointment  without prior notice",d:"indemnify him against injuries caused through negligence "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:522,question:"The information on terms of carriage of mails is found in",option:{a:"business journal",b:"post office guide",c:"trade directory",d:"service manual"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:99,question:"One advantage of a crossed cheque is that it can",option:{a:"only be paid into a savings account",b:"be cashed over the bank's counter",c:"only be paid into the owner's account",d:" be cashed by anyone"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:159,question:"Public relations and advertising are similar in terms of",option:{a:"communicating product information",b:"customer education ",c:"the mode of operation",d:"creating a favourable attitude."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:656,question:"The transformation of cotton into clothing is an example of",option:{a:"secondary production",b:"tertiary production",c:"primary production",d:"direct production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:79,question:"The availability of goods and services is brought to the notice of consumers through",option:{a:"personal selling  ",b:"public relations",c:"the telephone  ",d:"advertising."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:793,question:"Which of the following best describes the scope of commerce?",option:{a:"All forms of commercial exchanges and the manufacturing industry",b:"Buying and selling and the construction industry",c:"All occupational exchanges relating to industries and commercial activities",d:"Buying and selling as well as the extraction of natural resources."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:202,question:"In the long run, all factors of production are ",option:{a:"fixed ",b:"variable ",c:"marginal ",d:"constant "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:225,question:"An association to which all chambers of commerce in Nigeria are affiliated is the ",option:{a:"Nigeria Labour Congress ",b:"National Association of Chambers of Commerce, Industry, Mines and Agriculture",c:"Nigeria Association of Chambers of Commerce, Industry, Mines and Agriculture ",d:"Nigeria Stock Exchange "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:602,question:"Which of the following is one of the functions of commerce?",option:{a:"Manufacturing",b:"Growing of tomatoes",c:"Storage of goods",d:"Construction of Roads"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:778,question:"Which of these companies offers after-sales services?",option:{a:"IV",b:"Ill",c:"II",d:"I"},section:"Companies I, II, III and IV produce and sell electronic videos. Company I sells its videos for N= 14 000 each and offers advice on how to fix and operate them. Company II sells at N14 000 and its representatives go to install at no additional cost. Company III sells at N15 500 and offers credit sales at N15 500 per video while company IV sells at N= 15 000 each.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:166,question:"A document which advertises the shares of a company is known as a  ",option:{a:"memorandum of satisfaction   ",b:"dividend warrant     ",c:"deed",d:"prospectus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:261,question:"A collective term for advertising, personal selling and publicity is ",option:{a:"exhibition ",b:"promotion ",c:"trade fair ",d:"mechanizing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:622,question:"Which of the following is the most suitable means of 	transporting bulky goods from Lagos to Kaduna? By",option:{a:"Train",b:"Airplane",c:"Ship",d:"Lorry"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:30,question:"An action taken by a company outside its object clause is regarded as ",option:{a:"ultra vires    ",b:"a trespass   ",c:"uberrima fides    ",d:"caveat emptor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:643,question:"The amount paid by the insurance company to the insured upon giving up his policy is called",option:{a:"Surrender value",b:"cash bonus",c:"assured sum",d:"dividend"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:145,question:"The documents used in the purchase and sale of goods which contain other terms of trade are",option:{a:"debit note and credit note ",b:"delivery note and advice not   ",c:"invoice and order      ",d:"quotation and invoice."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:815,question:"A bill of exchange already accepted can be discounted by the holder in",option:{a:"the central bank",b:"at least two banks",c:"his bank",d:"any bank."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:164,question:"The making of doors from timber planks is a type of ",option:{a:"manufacturing ",b:"tertiary production",c:"secondary production   ",d:"primary production."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:221,question:"A document sent by a seller to inform a buyer about the prices of goods is the ",option:{a:"catalogue ",b:"price list",c:"credit note",d:"proforma invoice "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:691,question:"The form of credit sales common to low income groups is",option:{a:"hire purchase",b:"club trading",c:"book-me-down.",d:"credit trading."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,e as message,o as status,i as subject,a as total};
